

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Certified SAFe Agilist, Director seeking roles in IT Project Management, IT Service Delivery, Digital Transformation, Strategic Planning, Process Improvement, Stakeholder Management, Cost Optimization, Budgeting, Devops, Oracle, JIRA, SQL

Total Experience: 27 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Operations]

Current Designation: Director - Project (IT Service Delivery)

Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Role: Head/VP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Director, Head/VP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO, IT Project Management, IT Service Delivery, Digital Transformation, Strategic Planning, Process Improvement, Stakeholder Management, Cost Optimization, Budgeting, Devops, Oracle, JIRA, SQL Server, Certified SAFe Agilist.

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

An accomplished professional, with diversified experience in driving vision across Delivery Management (Project/Program), Pre-sales, P&L, Stakeholder Management; participated in RFP responses and acquired large deals/contracts above USD 100MN. Delivery Excellence Business Leader with hands-on experience in directing implementation and delivery of multimillion dollars projects across the globe with focus on achieving top-line & bottom-line results. Diligently led the offshore delivery implemented DevOps solutions and achieved zero defect delivery, 80% code coverage, 2.15% defect leakage against BIC standard of 4%. Excellence in managing a portfolio of worth USD125Mfor Digital Engineering Practice. Consistently grew & augmented the bottom-line and top-line of key accounts and managed a team of Delivery Managers, Project Managers and Consultants

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Director - Project (IT Service Delivery) Dec 2010 to Till Date

(Assignements: Service Delivery Leader for Global Logistics Solution - Retail Program to largest fortune 10 retailer, Program Manager to Medicaid Management Information System (MMIS) - Health Enterprise Platform for Client Xerox, Digital Delivery Partner to CVS Health Account, Engineering Director to Healthcare East Strategic Business Unit)

Growth Path:

Senior Manager Associate Director Director - Project

Key Result Areas:

- Directing strategic IT functions including IT Portfolio Roadmap, Service Delivery in collaboration with diverse team members; supervising cost budgeting, target achievement strategies & service operations including KPIs & SLAs
- Developing defend and growth strategies and to implement strategic initiatives for additional revenue generation, cost reduction & customer satisfaction.
- Facilitating discussions to elicit and understand business needs, requirements & priorities; driving prioritization and end-to-end project management with senior stakeholders and providing insights for design & business process
- Participating in CXO, SVP connect sessions through video conference for regular cadences on Quarterly Business Reviews, governance to gather customer requirements
- Implementing strategic vision, infused new ideas and took business performance to the next level; driving revenue, target achievement strategies & contributing in architecting solutions in accordance with the requirements
- Defining service standards and guidelines, governance structure, best practices that worked as benchmark for excellent service delivery across the globe for all verticals with end-to-end P&L accountability
- Delivering PMO leadership for successful execution of projects within defined time, budget & quality timelines
- Leading, mentoring & monitoring the performance of team members to ensure efficiency in process; developing competency among the team members; conducting interviews to recruit the right talent in niche transformational space
- Identifying & exploiting the transformation opportunities and understanding business themes to implement digital

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

- iSOFT R&D Private Limited as Senior Manager Nov 2005 to Dec 2010
- Healthcare Solutions as Application Consultant Mar 1999 to Nov 2005

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Not Specified) from University of Chennai, india in 1993

PG: MBA/PGDM (Operations), Correspondence/Distance Learning from IGNOU, NEW DELHI in 2005

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:
PG Diploma in Systems Management
SAFe Agilist and AWS certified Cloud Practitioner
Executing Complex Programs from Stanford Advanced Project Management Certificate Program
Certified Bullet Proof Manager (BPM)

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
DevOps, Agile, VSS, Clearcase		
AWS, MS Project, SVN, JIRA		
Visual Basic, Oracle, MUMPS		
SQL Server, Crystal Report		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				
Malayalam				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.